I think you should know
that this is not my wife
and I'm not really interested
in classical music.
I--I just made
a huge mistake.
It's the kind of mistake
that any married man might make
after 25 years,
but believe me,
I can promise you,
this will never happen again.
One bad rodeo clown
ruins the whole barrel.
It was a bad year
for grapes...
Oh!
That looks so great.
It's so beautiful.
Oh, and I'm going to make
a little toast, if I may.
To our friends--
to our good friends.
Our best friends.
Best friends--
to our best friends.
This is in celebration
of 25 years of marriage.
Perfect marriage.
And--
and in anticipation of
25 more years like it.
Oh, that's sweet.
I love you.
OK, blow 'em out,
pal.
OK, come on.
Blow, blow, blow, blow.
Oh!
It's a light cake.
Look at his nose.
* Yeah, man,
come on *
* Ah, yes
Eh, bonjour.
Welcome back, Mrs Stoddard.
Can I help you
with any of that stuff?
Nice to see you again.
Just bring it
in here.
Missed him.
Hi.
Hi, Yolanda. Hello.
Hiya, Dad.
Hey!
How are you?
How was it?
Oh, it was great!
Great.
You want to help us
with these things?
Yeah. I'm on the phone with
Holly. She's coming for dinner.
Who's Holly?
She's a friend of mine.
You're gonna like her.
Good.
Holly.
What happened
to Miranda?
What happens to any of them?
They turn 18.
They're old, they're wrinkled,
they're discarded.
Hi!
Hi, Mom. Did you
have a good time?
Such a good time. Wait till you
see what I got.
There's a person
in the kitchen.
That's Omar.
It's Omar, Porter.
You remember Omar, Dad.
Oh, yeah.
Omar. Omar.
Omar!
Come say hello.
Hello, Omar.
You know, he's shy.
Don't think about it.
Don't worry about it.
Let me ask you.
There are people,
they have daughters,
who have boyfriends
who actually speak.
He speaks. I've heard him speak.
He just doesn't speak
in a language that,
I happen to know.
That's all.
It's Turkish.
Turkish? I don't think so.
More like Arabic or Farsi.
Anyway,
he's very sweet. Ugh.
OK. Sweet is good.
Who cares?
We're back home.
I love you.
I can't believe it.
Who was it?
I don't know.
I don't know, honey.
Uh, Yolanda,
could you just, uh,
lift that up
for me a little?
Thank you.
Gracias.
Um, uh, Yolanda's
new boyfriend...
Alejandro.
When did Alejandro
move in?
The day after
you and Mom left.
He's a good guy, Dad.
And why is Alejandro
not wearing a shirt?
That's what he's used to--
living in the jungle.
Living in a jungle?
I'm just curious.
Why would he be
living in a jungle?
Because that's where
his group lived.
His group.
Is that botanists?
No, his political
group.
El compa?eros
de la muerte.
"The companions
of death?"
That's colourful.
Yeah. They plan to overthrow
their government
and establish a regime
of democratic ideals
and crop sharing.
No better place to start
than right here on Fifth Avenue.
Central Park has always needed
a good crop-sharing program.
Ha! Ha.
That--that's really
fucking funny.
Dad, did you see,
uh, Holly's stud?
Holly's stud?
Show him, Holly.
Isn't that great?
Let me see.
You ever worry
about swallowing it?
Yeah. Actually I did twice,
but I got it back.
How--how did, uh...
Ooh.
It's been a long day.
I'm gonna pack it in.
Uh, me, too.
Honey, I'm just--
No. Omar wants
to say something to you.
Really? You do?
That's wonderful.
Huh?
Mizz, Misserrr...
Stob--
Stodd.
Stodd?
Stoddard.
Honey.
Stobb-ard.
Stoddard.
Welgome.
Wel-goom...
hone.
Oh, OK.
Welgoom hone.
Hone.
Huh. Hone. Home. Welcome home.
That's so nice of you.
Very good.
Very well said.
Thank you. Thank you.
Hey, Steve!
Congruity with
the rest of the--
What is the man saying?
That--that the frame for the
Millennium Museum of
Architecture shouldn't be making
an architectural statement?
I mean, you got to make
a statement.
The thing is a--is a gateway.
It's beautiful.
Absolutely.
It's perfect.
What is Mrs Hadley
making for lunch?
She's making romoroli.
Romoroli?
Mm-hmm.
What's romoroli?
Oh, it's this Indonesian thing.
Little pieces of meat and fish
sort of jammed together
on a stick.
Oh, good, good. I hate
little pieces of meat and fish
jammed together
on a stick.
Sweetie,
it's not for you.
It's for the design conference
people from Japan. Remember?
What are they coming
here for?
They want to see my design...
and they want to meet everybody.
No! Aah.
Ohh!
Oh, my God!
Get away!
Get away from her!
Are you
all right?
Don't worry.
Here.
Oh. All right.
Oh, my God. Here.
Are you OK? Come on.
Why don't you go inside.
Come on, girl.
Get over here. Come on!
Come on!
Weathered
shingles.
Double-hung
windows...
Hello! Hi!
Welcome. Hi.
Sorry, everybody. I'm thrilled
to introduce you to my son
and my daughter.
This is Alice and Tom.
Thank you.
Anyway, I'm sure everybody
must be hungry.
Oh. Oh!
Mrs Stoddard, I think your
handyman just fell off the roof.
Oh, my God.
Oh! Oh, no, no.
Oh, no, he's fine.
That's Porter. That's just...
Her Porter
fell off the roof.
Porter is--
Porter's my husband.
Sirs, that's fine.
That's OK. He's fine.
Thank you. Don't worry.
Have some of this lovely cake.
Hello?
Oh?
What?
Where?
You're joking.
You're not joking?
Oh...
Excuse me. Have you
seen Mr Stoddard...
anywhere?
Who?
Porter!
Hey, ho,
what's going on?
I'm very angry with you,
Porter Stoddard.
You're my oldest friend. How
could you let this happen?
What?
What are you
talking about?
How could you not tell me?
You know every move of Griffin.
Who is she?
Yeah, who is she?!
It's not insane! I saw them!
I went. I followed them.
What'd he say?
What did he say?
I will never speak
to that man again.
Never!
You probably saw him
with some client.
Oh, play golf.
Play golf.
A client,
for God's sakes.
You'll be next,
gentlemen.
Ow! Ooh!
Carlos, I'm so--
I'm sorry, Carlos.
Ellie, I think, uh,
we've got a problem.
Which one?
Social problem.
No, no, no.
Which one of these?
Mona caught Griffin.
Porter, could just help me for
one second.
Now, I have
to submit 7 samples.
If you were on this
awards committee, right,
which one would you be
most impressed by, huh?
Did you hear what I said?
Mona caught Griffin.
Yeah, Mona caught Griffin.
Yeah, I heard you, darling.
What was he doing?
Oh, wait.
You don't mean
that he--
Yes, I do.
I don't believe it.
No. You should
believe it.
He couldn't possibly
do that.
He--he did it.
With who?
Some redhead.
She saw them.
She saw them
doing what?
Doing what?
What people do when they--
Porter, please,
please get off my floor!
Honey, I'm sure it's all
just a mistake.
She said she's gonna
divorce him.
No, she won't. What do you
think? Plaid or boutique?
But I'll tell you,
on this finger,
the wedding ring
is not--oh!
You know, whatever
this big secret is,
it better be worth
getting lime disease.
Ha ha ha.
Are you having
an affair?
No.
Huh, no.
Ha ha ha ha!
No.
Yes, I am.
Not good.
I--I need to know
how you know about this
because I don't want
Mona to find out about it.
Mona told me.
Huh?
She followed you this afternoon.
She followed you
What did she say?
She saw you with some redhead
in some motel off the highway.
What did you say for me?
That's all I'm asking.
I stood up for you,
but I don't have material here
to work with, do I?
What is going on?
What's the matter
with you?
How come she hasn't said
anything to me about it?
She hasn't said
anything to me about it.
Maybe she won't.
You all right?
Are you all right?
Go.
I--just...
I think I asked you
to leave me alone.
Don't look at me.
Mona, I--
Don't talk to me!
Can I think about you?
No.
Unh, yeah.
Oh, right there.
Oh, Holly.
Oh, my God.
Holly!
Ohh!
Don't stop!
Oh, God!
Ahh, Omar.
Omar!
Omar! Omar!
Omar! Aah.
Aah!
Yolanda!
Dios mio, Papi!
Ah, Omar.
Sit down.
Heshushatoona.
Hesh...
No, no, no.
It's, uh...
I--I never eat
heshbitshatoon
late at night.
"Riz... Riz..."
Rice Krispies.
Yeah.
Snag, kringle, poop.
Exactly. Yeah.
Hijole! Heh heh.
Alejandro, sit down.
Gracias.
De nada.
Ah, ha ha ha!
Hmm? No, no.
Thank you.
Oh. Ha ha ha.
Se?or worm.
Worm.
Muy bueno.
Give you
Tu sabes?
Jesus Christ.
Hola!
Join us.
Ah, Mr Stoddard.
A friend is waiting
for you upstairs.
Oh, good.
Calm? I am calm.
That's good.
And I made a decision
calmly and dispassionately...
That's good.
To string Griffin up
by his balls.
Mona!
Please, please try
the chocolate mousse.
It's a poem.
Thank you
very much.
She's called a lawyer.
What lawyer?
Suttler.
Suttler?
David "The Shark"
Well, I didn't read
the whole card.
Who recommended him?
You did.
I don't know how you got
yourself into this thing.
I just--I don't--
I don't get it.
Come on. Are you telling me
that in 25 years you haven't--
No.
One--
You haven't one time?
No.
You're kidding.
Not once?
No.
Ever?
Oh, come on.
No. I'm not making
a big deal.
Have you thought
about it?
I'm a normal guy. OK?
Well.
Several times
I've thought of it.
Thought about it
numerous, numerous,
numerous times.
Numerous times, but, you know,
you really think
that I'm some kind of a--
of a...
a stiff.
I was gonna say prude.
OK?
But you get
to a certain age...
some things become important
that weren't important before.
We're not kids anymore. What is
important is continuity...
Mm-hmm.
Stability...
I don't know how you got
yourself into this situation.
You know, sometimes
you're very judgemental.
Which way you going?
Uh, what, uh,
which way you going?
Downtown.
Yeah. OK.
I'll see you later.
OK.
Ohh!
Let's be realistic
about this, though.
I am being
realistic.
As I recall, you had a thing
few years ago.
Not to bicker--
I mean, I don't--what?
I'm talking about Hans.
Hans?
I--I don't know
anybody named Hans.
Oh, you mean Fritz.
Oh, yeah, exactly.
I mean Fritz.
Yeah, but you know what?
Fritz was 11 years ago,
Griffin and I had an argument,
he was from Europe,
he didn't speak English,
so it does not count.
It doesn't count, huh?
No.
Oh, I wish
I had known that.
Can I say something?
Could you think about compassion
or even possibly
forgiveness?
What about betrayal?
What about humiliation?
Look. I understand
how you feel.
You don't know
how I feel, Ellie.
Imagine
if it was Porter.
Oh, that's absurd. Porter would
never do anything like that.
Well, of course not. It's not
his style. He's like a rock.
Ever been married?
I am married.
Huh?
Hmm.
He reminds me
of you.
Really.
Yeah.
Yeah. He's really,
really mature.
Really.
That's what I love most, you
know-- maturity, dependability.
Mm-hmm. Where is he?
He's right over there.
Hmm. Heh.
He's over
200 years old.
Huh. Hmm.
Must be exhausted.
Unh! Huh!
Forget your umbrella,
did you, Mr Stoddard?
Yes, uh...
yes, I did.
Uh, Barney, you got any idea
what time it is?
Uh, 10 past 11.00,
Mr Stoddard.
Thank you, thank you.
Did you forget your watch,
too, Mr Stoddard?
Yes, I did, Barney.
Thank you.
What about books?
So architecture should be
like great works of art.
So what you feel...
How'd you make out?
What?
With Griffin--
how'd it go?
Fine. Just fine.
He's gonna do
what's best.
For who?
Mona, uh, for himself,
and, uh...
yeah.
Ahem.
No. Hey, don't do that, please.
I was watching.
You were sleeping.
No, I wasn't.
Your eyes were closed.
I was watching
through my eyelids.
You're very strange.
Yes, I am, aren't I?
Yes.
But strange is good,
isn't it?
Sometimes, yeah.
That's what he said on
television.
He was saying that about new
buildings.
That they work best when they're
a combination of the new--
no, not the new,
I mean the strange.
Uh, strange and familiar.
Strange and familiar.
Yeah.
Phillip Johnson.
New buildings like
old relationships.
That's very good.
Very good.
Where you going?
Uh, kitchen. Gonna get
something sweet.
Honey...
there's a cello
in the fridge.
What did you say?
I said, "There's
Jello in the fridge."
I consider it my duty
as a first step to ask you
to take some time, revisit your
true feelings for each other,
and consider the gravity of this
step you're about to take.
I think that's
a good idea.
Don't you?
OK, I'm finished.
Excellent.
Let's move on.
All right. Now...
I have here a complete list
of all your possessions,
real estate, securities,
East Hampton house,
Mississippi house,
art objects, et cetera.
All of which
are in your name.
Who advised you on this?
You did.
Right. Ahem.
Except for one item.
A cabin in Sun Valley.
It's near
Sun Valley.
It's not near
Sun Valley, Griffin.
It's in Sun Valley.
How do you wish
to dispose of it?
He can have it.
Thank you.
* Both day and night
* And night and day
* You're gonna see
a lot of me *
What are you
thinking?
I'm thinking women know.
Women know?
I knew that this
was gonna happen.
I knew it.
You want to be honest
about this thing?
You want to just put it
out on the table?
I knew when we came here
that very first time.
You remember when Griffin didn't
even look at Mona?
It was like Mona
was somebody in Cleveland.
He was, like, completely
fixated on that idiot--
Yeah. Ha ha!
What's so funny?
Yeah. No. I know.
You're right.
He was looking at that
hat-check girl.
Yeah.
It was embarrassing.
But, let's be fair to the guy.
I mean, he's--
I just feel
badly for Mona.
I feel badly for her.
She's my oldest friend,
but I feel--
She's lost.
Actually, she's lost,
Porter.
I think you should go
and help her.
You should help her with that
house down in Mississippi.
Sure. Want me
to do that?
Would you do that for me?
Sure. Sure.
Do you know
how lucky we are?
I do know.
Oh, I could kick myself
for not seeing this coming.
Come on. Nobody
saw it coming.
You all right?
No. Don't speak.
I'm having a little trouble
breathing, that's all.
Look at me.
What?
Look at what he's doing to me.
I'm a mess.
Why do you want to give
so much power?
You're an amazing woman. You got
a second chapter ahead of you.
Really?
Of course you do.
I wouldn't lie to you.
Really?
Of course not.
Come on.
You know, I'm gonna start
that new second chapter off
with a wee-wee.
Hi. My name is
Porter Stoddard.
Eugenie.
I'm, uh...
An architect.
Yeah,
I'm an archi--
How did you know
I was an architect?
I love to fuck architects.
Heh heh!
OK.
That's your way of
making fun of me?
Yes.
Well, very nice, uh,
nice meeting you,
whoever you are.
THANKS.
We're here.
This is it.
Great. Great.
I knew you'd love it.
Just look at this house!
Wow!
Oh!
Uh, what is all that
growing around there?
Oh. Excuse me,
what's this called?
Kudzu.
It's Kudzu, Porter.
Kudzu. Yeah.
I'm going to live here...
Full time?
With my people.
When did you
decide that?
Just now I thought of it.
What do you think?
Well, I think it's a little
isolated, to tell you the truth.
Well, I'm so trapped
in New York,
and I want to
live off the land.
Live off the land. Huh.
This is my home.
This feels--Porter,
this is worth saving.
Yeah, a little
painting, plumbing,
you know,
re-strip the floors.
Yeah. Come on. I want
to show you something.
Well, this place looks
good. I think this is terrific.
If you don't go out,
how are you gonna meet people?
It's amazing!
I am so happy.
Why don't you give him
a little smile?
A smile?
Smile.
OK.
What?
I'm very rusty at all of this.
This is just, you know--
That's normal. That's normal.
Come on. Give him another smile.
Oh, my God.
Give him something.
Give him...
There you go. It's
like riding a bicycle!
Once you know how,
you know how.
I'm gonna go
to the ladies' room.
That's a good idea.
Good.
* I can't
stand the rain *
Excuse me.
Do we know each other?
Oh, no.
I don't think so, no.
You want to dance?
Yeah. OK.
* Came with the rain
* Do you remember
* Ooh, how sweet
it used to be? *
* When we were together
* Everything
was so grand *
* No, I can't stop
The rain on my windowpane *
Can't stop... oh.
Oh, honey,
you are--
oh, you are--
you big, strong,
reliable, steady-
as-a-fucking-rock,
beautiful friend.
It's hot.
I'm sorry about
the air conditioning.
What air conditioning?
Exactly.
Heh!
I--I--good night.
Are you OK?
Huh?
I think we have
a family of bats.
Yeah. It's fine.
You know, I think there's some
kind of an insect
in my water there.
Look what I found.
What's that?
Look.
Heh heh!
That's--that's
our--that's--
that's the
Fourth of July.
I'm 17. I think
I'm 17 there.
I think you're, what?
I'm 12.
I think
you're still 12.
That's your
father's old truck.
You know, he never--
* Doo *
* Doo doo doo
doo doo doo *
* Doo doo doo doo
* Doo doo doo
doo doo doo doo *
Mona?
* Doo doo doo
doo doo doo doo *
Mona?
Mona!
Come here, poochie.
Come on.
Welcome back, Mr Stoddard.
How are you?
Fine.
Do you know if Mrs Stoddard is
upstairs?
She's at a movie with your kids
and the Armenian fella.
Your daughter's
boyfriend.
You think
he's Armenian, huh?
Ooh, a lady came by and
dropped this for you.
Ah! My watch. That's great.
Thanks. Thanks. Thanks.
She was
a beautiful girl.
Beautiful,
was she? Uh-huh.
She was kind of
dirty blonde.
Yeah. Dirty blonde.
Beautiful
and dirty blonde.
Well, you know,
she fixed my watch.
My watch was broken,
and so she fixed it for me.
That's what she does.
She's an expert in watches.
Also clocks.
Very expert.
Hey. Hey, hey, boys.
Hello?
Anybody home?
Hey, you're back.
That looks good.
Yeah.
God, am I hungry. Honey, no.
Let me do that for you.
I'm better with
a knife than you are.
Go sit down.
That's OK.
You went to the movies
with the kids?
Yeah. But I want to know about
Mona. What's going on?
Fine. She's fine.
What'd you see?
Well, Tom and Holly
saw this movie
filled with all
these dirty jokes
that they had to
repeat to me,
most of which, of course,
I didn't understand.
Do you know what
corn-holing is?
Corn-holing?
Mm-hmm.
Uh, after
my sandwich, OK?
I'm worried
about Mona, though.
Why?
Think she's getting laid?
Getting laid?
Yeah, as a professional,
what's your opinion?
What does that mean?
I mean, as a man.
What's your opinion?
I haven't given it
any thought.
I'll tell you what I think.
She has a high aptitude for sex.
I'm surprised
you haven't noticed.
You've been
friends forever.
I'll ask her.
What movie did you see?
Oh, God. You would
hate this movie so much.
It was a woman's movie, OK?
It was about this sweet woman
married to this sweet man,
then she discovers that he's
having an affair
with his secretary, only he
doesn't know she knows,
and then she just loses it,
she pushes him out the window.
Oh. So she's a murderer.
This sandwich
is so delicious.
He doesn't die.
Oh, yeah. He's just
completely broken up.
He can't walk, he can't talk,
and then she takes him home
after this series of
very painful operations,
and she nurses him
back to health, and then...
she kills him.
She pushes him
out the same window.
Anyway, can you tell Mona
that I really want to talk
to her about this whole mess?
This was so good.
You ought to try one.
Let's sit
down and talk, OK?
I think--I think--
I think we ought to
sit down a minute.
You know, I think
if we sit down,
and we just talk, OK?
I think we need to
talk about this.
I think we go on like
nothing ever happened.
We make a--a--pfft--
clean slate.
Door's open.
Porter.
Uh...
uh, anybody here?
No.
I think, uh...
I think we've got to
talk about this.
Yeah. Don't even
say it. I'm there.
Really?
Yeah.
We just go on like
nothing ever happened?
Yeah. Nothing
ever happened.
Great.
People make mistakes.
That's right.
We made a mistake.
We'll give ourselves
a--pfft--clean slate.
Clean slate.
Mona!
Oh, my God.
It's Ellie.
Get up. Get up.
Mona!
Go in the bedroom.
Hey, Mona?
Mona!
Oh, yeah.
Hi. Hi.
Mona, Porter's
having an affair.
No!
Yes.
How'd you find
that out?
Somebody called me.
A friend.
Friend?
What kind of
friend is that?
He's having a affair
with a musician.
Oh, a musician.
Yes.
Oh.
A cellist.
That's not possible.
Let me get you
a cup of coffee.
I don't know
what I'm gonna do.
This is just
beyond belief.
You know something?
I'm being paid back
for being so damn smug
about my own marriage.
I am so sorry, Mona.
I wasn't very understanding
of what you were going
through with Griffin,
but now that it's happening to
me, ha ha! Oh, boy.
No. Don't be
too hard on yourself.
Morning.
What are you
doing here?
I just came
to get my things.
Well, you can't
just walk in here.
What do you need?
I need my sport coats.
You have to call
me ahead of time.
I need to go through lawyers
to get my coats.
Yes. Otherwise, I'm gonna get
a restraining order!
Oh. For my sport coats?
Yeah.
And my special hangers?
Hello, Ellie.
Wait a minute!
Get down here.
Let me tell you.
It's not a good time.
This isn't a good time for me.
I have to be seen driving a van.
Wait a minute.
What do you need?
I need my sport coats
and my special hangers.
All right. Stay right there.
Don't come up here.
So, what's new, Ellie?
Well, you know...
None of it's easy.
Oh, where are you?
Oh, all this because of me.
How do I do this?
Is he coming upstairs?
Are you fucking a cellist?
Oh!
You better have a damn good
story when you get home.
Here's your sport coats,
and go with God.
Hey, did you see my
golf shoes up there?
No. You took
your golf shoes.
No, I didn't. I think
they're up there.
No, they're not up
there. They're not there.
I'll get them, 'cause I have
to go to the bathroom anyway.
Mona. Mona. Mona.
I really don't know what I'm
gonna do. I mean, you know,
I mean, absolutely being
realistic in a marriage,
I mean, is never as simple
as one person doing
something to the other person
without the other person being
somehow complicit, am I right?
Mm-hmm.
I can't believe
what I just saw.
How could you have?
How could you have
used my shaver?
This is hair from your leg.
We had this discussion.
Your hair
is all over it.
You're insane.
Listen.
Huh?
You know what you have to do?
No.
You have to confront him.
He's in the city.
Let's go.
Are you gonna come with me?
Yeah.
All right.
I'll get my keys.
Get your car.
Yeah. All right.
Mona, thank you. You're such a
good friend.
Thank you so much.
You would
actually think
that I would put our marriage
into that kind of jeopardy?
You think I would put our
marriage into jeopardy?
No. You actually--
you actually think that
I would put our marriage
into that kind
of jeopardy?
You actually think
I'd put our marriage
into that kind
of jeopardy?
You actually think--
you actually think that
I would put our marriage
into that kind
of jeopardy?
You would...
just think about it.
Look. Here he is.
Porter!
Well, how are you?
How are you?
Such wonderful news.
What are you
doing here?
Your housekeeper said
you were on your way.
My housekeeper? You
spoke to my housekeeper?
I was waiting here, but I only
have a few minutes to go back.
OK. Well, honey,
I'll get you a cab.
Barney, you want to get a cab
for the young lady?
I've got such
wonderful news.
Alex, listen.
You can't be late for rehearsal,
'cause rehearsals are sacred,
you know? News,
news happens every day.
Taxi!
Listen to me!
It's too amazing. I'm so happy
ever since I got the report.
You know,
from the doctor.
Barney.
What--what are you--
what are you--
are you telling me-- are you
telling me that you're pregnant?
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
How do I look?
All right.
Isn't it remarkable?
That's it. Remarkable.
Tell me you're happy for me.
And proud? You're proud?
I want you to be proud.
Proud, yes, proud.
'Cause you know what? All my
life, I wanted everything,
and now I've got it all--
my life, my music, my baby.
Your taxi.
Yeah, OK.
Good. Good.
We'll talk about
this later, OK?
I hope so.
Be happy, Porter.
You, too, Barney.
Be happy.
Sweet girl, huh?
Hi.
Ahem.
What's going on?
Everything OK?
Porter, I want to
ask you a question.
All right. Before you answer it,
I want you to think about
what marriage is. I mean,
to me, marriage is about trust.
That's all it is, and I believe
an honest marriage
can survive anything,
but a dishonest marriage--
to me, it's
no marriage at all.
Right.
Are you having an affair?
Of course.
Porter.
Wh--what--wh--
Are you asking me if
I'm having an affair?
Are you serious?
Is she serious?
Hilarious! Ha ha ha!
Well, I better be going.
No, no.
No, no. Wait a minute.
No, Mona. Stay.
Stay! Stay!
All right. We can just forget
it. It's not important.
It's not important?
If somebody's saying something,
I'd like to know what it is.
Well, a friend of mine
said that she saw you
with a young woman.
A cellist.
And you actually think that
I would put our marriage
into that kind of jeopardy?
Well, I don't know,
Porter. I just--
I got scared.
Scared?
Don't you think it might
be a good idea
to take a look at this person
and examine whether or not
they actually are your friend,
you know?
Because if you needed to,
you could always
find a hundred special
prosecutors to come up
with a story you're looking for,
but it might be a good idea
if you would just examine
yourself and why you need
to believe something
that would make you pursue
a sordid little fishing
expedition like this.
This is--this is--
well, no. I guess you--no.
You have the temerity,
you have the audacity,
you have the heartlessness,
without a shadow of
a fraction of a moment
of a scintilla of
a tiny atom of a doubt
to think that I would
put our marriage
into that kind
of jeopardy?
That's just fine, Ellie!
Oh, that's just fine!
25 years! I would have
thought better of you, Ellie,
but that's fine!
That's fine! Good! Fine!
25 years!
Her name is Alex.
She does play the cello.
You son of a bitch!
Oh, Ellie.
Yeah. It's
all right. I knew.
I knew it.
I knew this.
This is exactly what
you would fall for--
some struggling
musician
you could take care of,
with a big, resonating box
between her legs.
God damn it, Porter.
We have been together for so
many years, I think I forgot
how little backbone
you actually have.
An honest marriage can survive
anything. You just said--
Oh, this is about you
and your big, stupid cock.
See you later.
So, uh, wh-what are you saying?
You don't want to work it out?
Look around you, Porter.
Look at this life,
and when you realize
how much work it took
to make you the completely
successful man you are
instead of the sneaky,
pussy-crazed slob
you were genetically
programmed to become,
then maybe
you can understand,
insofar as it is possible
for you to understand,
how deeply I hurt.
You're right.
You know, Porter,
I'm afraid this one's
a little out of my league.
I'm gonna let you
handle this on your own.
I mean, other emergencies, you
know, like life-threatening
illnesses and things like that,
I think I'm the kind of person
you want on your team,
but the cellist?
You'll forgive me if I don't
join you for dinner tonight.
Oh, shoot.
Ha! OK. OK.
Ha ha ha!
Ha!
OK. Uhh!
Aah!
Asshole. OK.
Hey.
You look awful.
Thanks.
Have you talked to Ellie
on the phone?
I can't.
She's threatened to take
out a restraining order.
Yeah. Mona's
answering machine says,
"Hi, it's Mona.
Leave me a message.
I'll call you unless
I've ever been married to you."
Well, she's funny.
Yeah, funny.
And smart.
Smart and sexy,
don't you think?
Sexy?
Um...
Griffin, I don't think people
who are really friends
should keep secrets
from each other.
That's absolutely right.
I didn't see it coming. I just
didn't. I didn't see it coming.
I just didn't.
I didn't.
No. Of course not. How could
you? I mean, you know why?
Because it's something
you hide and then you deny.
Well, I mean,
nobody planned it.
Of course not.
It's programmed.
It's genetic.
You really believe that?
It happened to me. It could have
happened to either of us.
I guess that depends
on how you feel about Ellie.
She's--I mean, uh...
How I feel about Ellie?
Like you and whoever
the redhead was,
that--I'm sure that you
were just looking for...
something that was
out of the ordinary,
something that--
Different.
Different, yeah. Ellie is a
woman, Mona's a woman,
and they're very complicated.
They're very... complicated.
We think we know all--
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
For God's sake,
what you're saying
is so interesting.
You're saying that--
Yeah.
No, not--but--
I'm not saying that necessarily
is the case, because--
But that they could?
Does that shock you?
No, no, no. Frankly,
it gets me a little hot.
Ha ha ha!
Gets you hot.
Yeah.
Really?
Have you ever
seen them kiss?
Yeah, well, they
kiss all the time.
Really? With tongues?
Griffin, what are we
talking about?
Huh?
What? I don't know.
I thought I was just gonna tell
you that I'm...
What?
I was gonna tell you that
I'm--I'm... going to Sun Valley.
Oh, to the cabin, huh?
Yep.
Well, that's smart.
Get away from everything
and just get
a clear perspective.
You want to go with?
Why would I do that?
To get away,
get a clear perspective.
Oh. Smart.
Yeah.
What would we
do there?
What difference does it make?
You're sleeping in the office.
She's talking about
a restraining order.
Listen, as people get older,
they become more who they are,
and accepting that
can be very freeing.
Sun Valley, it's so
inspirational.
There's this bracing air and
these cold spring torrents
and then there's these little
kind of all weird little
animal species, and that's just
inside. What do you say?
Well, it worked for
Ernest Hemingway, didn't it?
Maybe Sun Valley could be
the perfect solution.
Hemingway, our greatest writer,
he returned to Idaho
to the sky and the snow
and the stars,
and he communed with nature.
He fished, he hunted,
he wrote, he...
he shot himself.
Oh, well.
Huh, yeah.
Nice.
What do you think?
Nice wood. Nice wood.
Who built it?
Actually, beavers built it.
There used to be a river
that flowed
right through here.
Really? And the telephone?
Where's the telephone?
There is no phone. I told you it
was just you, me, and wolves.
This place cleans
up so nicely.
What are the sleeping
arrangements?
That's it.
Just one mattress.
You don't snore, do you?
No. Only in the day time.
At night I just,
you know, tend to weep.
Why don't
I take the couch?
Because then, it'll be
like we're married.
Yeah, I think we'll be
very happy together.
Well,
you know, or not.
Yeah. Or not.
This is...
freezing.
Oh!
I'm OK.
Ahem.
Do you have worms?
Fly fishing?
Yeah.
You never fly fish
with anything alive.
Dead worms.
What are you gonna be
doing for Halloween?
Where are you fishing?
The river.
Did you ever consider
getting a spinning outfit?
Maybe for Halloween,
huh?
Uh, how deep
is this river?
Not very deep. Do you want
beetles, ants, or wet nymph?
Uh...
Wet nymph?
A bug in its nymph phase.
Floats to surface,
hatches, dries its wings,
flies into a bush,
crashes into the water,
lays eggs and dies.
Oh, my God.
Where's the male?
Miles away.
Well, isn't that
a familiar story? Ha ha.
Heh heh.
Oh. No,
your pumpkin.
This is Ellie Stoddard.
I'm not in, or I'm asleep.
Leave a message.
Ellie, it's me.
Pick up, will you?
Ellie, will you please pick up?
I need to talk to you.
Alice, don't even
think about it. All right?
I need to talk to you.
Please?
Sorry--
Goes like this first.
Hold still. Got it.
Hello!
Hello! Up here!
Hi. Remember me from
the plane to Mississippi?
Oh, yeah. Yeah, sure.
My name's Eugenie.
Eugenie Claybourne.
Porter. Porter Stoddard.
Yes, I know.
Porter Stoddard.
This is my friend--
Griffin.
Griffin, uh...
Why don't you come see me?
I'm at the lodge.
Oh, uh, I don't
get into town much.
I really need to see you.
I have something very
important to tell you.
What about?
What do you--
Watch it. Watch it.
Watch it.
You all right?
Help.
Oh, I bruised myself
on the rock.
Hi.
How are you?
Oh, sit down.
Sit down.
You remember Griffin?
Griffin. Oh,
I love the name Griffin.
I had a lovely friend
named Griffin.
Lovelier than me?
He died terribly young.
Oh.
In Borneo.
We were to be married.
Sorry.
That is too bad.
A tribe found him floating in
his canoe, half-delirious,
and they took him
back to their wagas.
Wagas?
That's what they call
their huts.
Right.
And they tended to him and
nursed his wounds and all...
When he was better,
they cooked him and ate him.
Do you mean
they actually--
Do you mind if we don't talk
about this? It's upsetting.
Where are you going?
I'm going to my waga.
You can handle this
on your own.
It's amazing how much
this place has changed.
When my parents built their
house, it was just ranchers
and a few ski bums.
Your parents
have a house here?
My father still loves to ski.
He won a gold medal in biathlon.
The biathlon?
Skiing and shooting.
Wow. Shooting and skiing.
When was that? What Olympics?
I'm not telling you.
Uh-huh.
1952. Oslo.
Ha ha ha. Ahh...
He, uh, he came up here to be
with Ernest. He was devoted.
Ernest Hemingway?
Yes.
Are they here right now?
I'd love to meet 'em.
My parents?
Yeah.
Your parents are,
uh, very traditional.
They're gonna like you
very much.
Oh!
Buttons! Ha ha.
Daddy.
What the Sam Hill
is that noise? Mother?
Daddy,
this is Porter Stoddard.
You look a little soft.
Are you out of shape?
No. I do my 100 sit-ups
every day.
Unh.
Uh, hello.
Who's the stud?
Mother, this is
Porter Stoddard.
So, what brings you
up the mountain?
A vacation.
Vacation.
Heh. Kilimanjaro
is a snow-covered mountain
19,710 feet high,
said to be the highest
mountain in Africa.
The Western Summit
is called by the Massai
Negaji Negai--
a House of God.
Close to the summit lies
the dried and frozen carcass
of a leopard.
No one has ever explained
what the leopard was seeking
at that altitude.
Hemingway.
I understand that you were
an intimate of Hemingway's.
Intimate? Is that
some kind of homo thing?
Take your finger out of
your bunghole, paragreem.
Where's my drink?
Where's the swizzle stick?
Just stir it with that big
swinging dick of yours.
Aren't they
wonderful?
Uh, Eugenie tells me that you
won gold in the biathlon.
It was 1952. Norway.
It snowed heavily--
just give him his fucking drink,
you old muff-diver.
Mother, please.
Henry, you cocksucker,
could we have some ice
over here, please?
Don't pay
any attention to her.
Nah. Thank you.
Mother, I think you
really have a problem.
You are damned right
I have a problem.
He won't do it
to me anymore.
Yes, his limp carrot is
the root of all my problems.
All my doctors tell me so.
Cheers.
Every motherfucking
one of them.
Fucking...
going back upstairs.
Heh.
With 6-foot drifts, there's no
getting down
the mountain tonight.
So, good night, Stoddard.
You'll be sleeping
in Button's room,
and Button's
sleeping in my den.
Good night, sweetheart.
Good night, Daddy.
That tickles.
Ha ha ha!
Hi.
Oh, no.
What?
They can't be down here.
They'll be angry.
Who?
Huh?
Thomas has Stuffy.
Boogly Boo has Fluffy.
The other Ted has Pillow
and Floppy,
and Rocket has Stiffy.
Stiffy?
Yeah.
Do you think this is a good
idea? I think your father--
You're Floppy.
No, I just--
You be Floppy.
I'll be Fluffy.
Uh... oh, OK.
I'm Floppy?
Mmm.
Ohh! Ah!
Ahh! Ahh! Mmm. Mmm.
Uh, hi, Mr Claybourne.
We're just playing.
I'm, uh, I'm Floppy.
You know this game?
Yes. I know
Floppy well...
and all his friends.
Stoddard, I'm not a prude,
but... let me put it this way:
Button is a princess,
you see.
And that makes you the prince.
The prince must fight a dragon
to get to his princess.
I am that dragon.
And you, Button...
are my Boogly Boo.
Oh, Daddy.
Stoddard...
Night, Daddy.
Ah, OK.
I'm so sleepy.
You don't want to play?
Well, I'm
a little sleepy.
Hmm. Well,
let's just cuddle.
OK.
Just because you made
one bad choice in a woman
doesn't mean we
sit around all night.
I mean, there's
plenty of fish in the sea.
I wonder what fish say.
Hey, there's plenty of chicks
on the beach. Ha ha.
Hey,
look who's here.
Whoosh!
* Happy birthday to you
* Happy birthday,
Mr President *
* Happy birthday to you *
Remember?
From the hardware store.
You asked me what I was
doing on Halloween.
This is what I'm doing.
I'm gonna party with you guys.
That's fantastic.
We can't do that.
Why not?
Yeah. Why not?
Because we're on a sort
of a retreat.
Wow, who's reading
Solzhenitsyn?
That's fantastic. Aren't they
great, the Russians?
Dostoyevsky, Gogol, Turgenev.
All that gloom and loneliness
and desperation.
Are you guys gay?
Hey, I don't mind.
You know, couple of guys out
here in the middle of nowhere
reading books about men all
jammed in prison together.
Huddled together for warmth and
companionship.
Well, you know, there's no
reason we couldn't go
to the party for just, like, an
hour, huh?
What are you talking about?
Where are you going?
To get your costumes.
What do you think
of Pushkin, huh?
Hey, you're going
as Pushkin.
* A kiss on the hand
* May be quite continental
* But diamonds
are a girl's best friend *
* A kiss may be grand
* But it won't pay the rental
on your humble flat *
This is stupid, Tom!
Why would your father come to
a godforsaken place like this?
Maybe he wanted to get away
from irritating women.
Maybe that's it.
Where are you going?
I'm gonna see if anybody
here could help us, OK?
Champagne
and a cherry.
Will you get me
another margarita?
Thank you.
Hey, I need another
margarita. I'm sweating.
You're what?
I'm sweating.
You should be sweating. It's
hot, and you're a polar bear.
And we're in the continental
United States. Ha ha.
Listen, I want to go talk
to that spider by the door.
Which spider?
The one with the 6 legs.
Would you just keep Marilyn
occupied for a couple minutes?
No.
For the king?
For the king, you'd do it--
I need a margarita.
I'm sweating.
I think the straw
went down my leg.
He's the only one who
had sympathy from him
because he was so deaf
from the bells.
What?
He was deaf from
the bells, you know.
And Esmeralda is the
only one who felt bad
and had pity towards him
because he was deaf.
What?
He was deaf!
Hi. You know, I gotta tell you,
I'm a leg man,
and these 2 have
been driving me crazy.
The whole outfit.
It's fantastic.
Yeah. Yeah. Yours, too.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
Are you Elvis
or Evel Knievel?
Ha ha ha.
Heh heh heh.
I'm gonna have to get out
of here in a little bit, OK?
I'm sorry.
I'm not in a very...
* Sometimes your love
* Is just like cream
* So sweet and wild
* Sometimes your love
* It's just like a menthol
* So cool and nice
I still don't--
It's Elvis.
Oh. Heh. Elvis.
You know what? You're
wrong. You're wrong. That's all.
You're generalizing.
All men are not the same.
All I'm saying is that
in my experience--
What experience! You're 19 years
old, for godsakes.
You don't have
any experience!
All I'm saying is that
it's a scientific fact
that the connection
between the blood supply
to the brain
and the blood supply
to the penis
are basically the same.
Hey, you know what? Just don't
talk anymore, all right?
Grrr!
Aah! Aah! Aah!
What the hell is that?
Aah! Aah! Ha ha!
Aah! Ha ha ha.
There's gotta be a hole
in here somewhere.
Shh.
Uh-oh.
There's people here.
Tom!
What a surprise.
Dad?
Yeah. Tom...
and Holly...
I can't get
this thing off.
This is, uh, Auburn.
This is my friend Auburn.
This is Holly,
and this is Tom.
That's my son, Tom.
Oh.
Let's go.
Tommy. Tom.
Where you going, Tom?
Tommy?
OK, OK. If there's
one thing I know now,
it's that nothing
matters anymore
except going back
and fixing this mess,
making Ellie listen to me
whether she wants to or not.
Letting her see
how much I care,
just taking her in my arms
and saying,
"Ellie, I am your husband.
I am not a polar bear.
I am not a polar bear."
Stay here.
I wish he wouldn't
get so upset.
Well, he is upset.
That man left you
in the middle of the night
without a word.
Left you like
a used Kleenex.
Oh, mother, but if
it doesn't bother me.
Left you like
a $2.00 hooker.
Oh, dear.
Ha.
Well, did you kill it,
O great white asshole hunter?
If there's one positive thing
that's come from this trip,
it's that I've really grown
to love that cabin.
Oh, Alex, Alex, Alex,
Alex, Alex. How are you?
Oh, God.
I'm meeting Didi?.
Didi?, huh? Listen, listen.
Things are very clear now.
Things are very clear.
I'm completely committed
to my wife and my marriage and I
always will be, but I just--
I don't want you
to think that
I'm the kind of person
who's not going to step up
and take full
responsibility.
You know what I mean
by responsibility?
Full responsibility?
Huh? Uh, yeah, for
the baby, I mean.
A baby? A baby?
You're having a baby?
Oh, my God.
Of course, you'll be
taking responsibility
at your age.
What about your wife?
She must be thrilled
having a baby.
Taxi!
Don't you have, like,
2 grown children already?
Listen, there's nothing
to be frightened of, Porter.
There's nothing
to be frightened of.
Yeah, uh...
Um, Alex.
It sounds like you have
the perfect relationship.
Didi? and I do, too,
and it's not easy, because I'm--
I'm so unpredictable
and Didi?'s such a loner.
But when he found out
that he's gonna be a daddy,
that's like--it changed
everything between us,
you know?
Oh.
But listen, you know
when we first met?
Yeah.
I had no idea.
No idea? What?
That I was pregnant.
I had no idea.
Yeah. Wish me luck, OK?
Good luck, good luck.
Good luck, Porter.
Good luck.
Can I talk
to Tom, please?
Stoddard no aqui.
Ha ha! No aqui.
?Donde?
If you know what I mean.
Institute Design.
Institution of what?
OK. All right, uh,
gracias.
Hasta luego.
Tom, wait.
Shit.
Tom!
Now, if you'll pardon,
it's table number 11.
Your award will be
the penultimate.
The penultimate?
Oh, my God.
Oh, dear. OK, all right.
Prepare to bow.
Hello.
Porter... have you ever
stopped to think about
how little we know
about each other?
Good, good--
Sorry.
Thank you so much.
I would like to say a few words
about dinnerware and cutlery...
Mom.
Mom?
What?
Wouldn't it be nice
if dad were here?
I don't want to talk
about that now.
I know, but listen--
Aah!
Oh, my God.
Oh, you stained it.
I'll take care of it.
I'll handle it.
I'm sorry.
Oh, Alice.
She spilled some
wine on her, um...
Listen, I've got to tell
you about the redhead.
No, you don't.
Yes, I do.
Why?
Because we're best friends.
That's what best friends do.
They share certain
important details.
Not now, OK?
That looks awful.
You know what I'm gonna
do?
I'm just gonna lead a nice,
simple, quiet, contemplative,
celibate life. I'm just gonna
plunge into work. Excuse me.
You're very lucky that
you get to plunge into work.
And I have always been
so jealous of you, Ellie.
Oh, really?
Well, yeah, you're--
Well, let me tell you
something. Here's the truth.
I've always been
jealous of you.
What?
Yes, yes.
That cracks me up.
Why?
Because I think Porter always
had a kind of thing for you.
You did? Really?
Ellie--
Hi.
Hi, hello.
Oh, that's so sad.
That beautiful suit.
You need white wine.
White wine?
Pulls the red right out.
Oh. What were
you saying? Just--
What do you mean?
What I was saying?
About him
having, like, a thing--
That's a pretty
lipstick.
It's called Evening Rose.
You want to try it?
Oh, no.
Thanks very much.
It's for luck.
I wear it whenever I play.
What do you play?
Oh, Ravel, Stravinsky,
Bach, Haydn--
No, I meant
what instrument?
Ellie.
Huh?
This is a beautiful
building.
I just love architecture,
don't you?
My fianc? is an architect.
Architect?
We're going
to elope tonight.
Oh, that's
so romantic. God.
You should use
hair spray on that.
Hair spray?
I promise.
I de-stained an entire sofa
once with hair spray.
Let's try it.
Thank you very much.
You know, I have a friend
who is an architect.
Maybe your fianc?
knows him.
What's his name?
Hey, excuse me. This thing
isn't over, is it?
No, no, but I think
you've missed dinner.
That's OK.
I ate on the plane.
How'd you get
that yellow stain?
Yellow.
Actually, I wasn't even invited.
I'm sneaking in.
Why?
Oh, boy, it's
a long story. Um--
Mom.
Oh, all right.
OK, all right.
We're coming.
Bye-bye.
I've got to tell
you something.
Go ahead.
OK, this is difficult.
Just say it.
"Oh, tan-faced
prairie boy...
"before you came
to camp
"came many
a welcome gift.
You came taciturn
with nothing to give."
What are you
talking about?
"We but looked
on each other when lo,
more than all the gifts
in the world you gave me."
What?
"Old tan-faced
prairie boy."
Whitman.
Make the light,
please.
Hi.
What are you
doing here?
Well, I came
to see you. Why?
Porter, I want to tell
Mona something really,
really important.
What?
That I'm...
that I'm...
What?
What, what,
what, what?
That I'm--
Pay the man, will you?
Wait. Porter.
Porter, just a second.
Please, um...
And you came all
the way just to say--
Yeah,
I owed it to to you.
He also said, she is the only
woman that he has ever loved,
and he thinks about her all the
time, and you and your sister,
and that
without you all,
his life would
be meaningless.
Can't you understand? It's like
getting rid of this burden,
and now I can move
forward with my life,
you know, naked
and unashamed.
Well not,
you know, naked, but--
but certainly
not ashamed.
And none of this, Porter,
would have happened
if I hadn't gone into that
little cafe down in Tribeca.
All I wanted was a caf? au lait,
and I got Walter!
Wish me luck.
Ellie,
your handyman.
Oh, no. Shh...
Oh, this is--
Whoa!
I'm sorry.
This is not the place--
You're embarrassing--
you're embarrassing my family,
you're embarrassing
my friends,
and you're
embarrassing yourself.
Would you--
Please, pipe down.
Do we have
a problem here?
Just pipe down, OK?
OK, if somebody's
gonna pipe down,
I think you're gonna
be the one.
Security!
You don't have
to explain anything.
Oh, yes I do.
Let's go.
Mona, Mona, Mona.
Mona, I'm gay!
I'm a proud, gay,
human person.
Bravo.
Did he say "gay"?
Good night,
gentlemen. Good-bye.
Walter...
Where--
where are you going?
Porter, where
are you going?
What--Porter,
what are you doing?
Oh, that's a bad idea.
Our next awardee
has shown us
that the art
of fabric design
is not only alive
and well,
but flourishing--
Eleanor Stoddard.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, my God.
Ellie, Ellie,
Ellie, Ellie.
Oh, Roberta.
Thank you very much.
Ellie, Ellie,
Ellie, Ellie.
I--here.
Porter, Porter! Hi.
Oh. Hi.
Do you know her?
Uh, no, no.
The cellist?
Yes, yes.
Oh, man.
Oh, Porter.
She's the cellist,
right?
What?
Porter, listen, I--
I have to talk to you
about something else--
Hi.
Um...
Hello again. Hi.
Hi.
I would like
to tell you that you have
a really great son... and a
great husband. Nothing happened.
We were just in the snow,
and I was on top of him
kind of near his face
so it looked...
like, um, well,
he'll explain it to you.
Get some sleep, OK?
Is there any woman in this room
you haven't slept with, Porter?
Obviously not.
Everybody back.
Back.
Aah! Oh, my God.
Mr Claybourne.
Mr Stoddard.
You refused my hospitality, you
insulted my beloved daughter--
Drop the gun!
Sir, can you
explain who this man is?
Can you explain
any of this? Sir?
All right, can we just
turn our attention
to the last page
of the possessions list?
Is there anything
missing from it?
Yes, Willie
and Charlie.
Ooh, your children.
No, no, no.
Our dogs.
Yes, of course.
The dogs.
And I'll keep
the dogs.
The dogs are better off with me.
They're happier with me.
You're the one who
said they adored me.
They're intimidated by you.
They just pretend to adore you.
They're highly
intelligent dogs--
Let's settle
the dog issue--
They love being in the country
where they were trained.
I did that.
You did that.
The country.
I don't think we decided
who gets the house.
I have.
I designed the house--
it took 2 years.
I built those rooms with my
hands. Did you do that?
I furnished the house--
it took 7 years.
I gave birth to our kids with my
own loins. Did you do that?
So, I guess, uh, I'll be
living in the apartment.
Yeah?
Did I say that?
I don't believe I said that.
Hi.
Didn't mean
to scare you.
Oh, no,
you didn't scare me.
You startled me.
I just wasn't expecting--
To see me?
To see you.
Ever?
No, of course not.
Not ever.
I mean, I knew I'd bump
into you someday. Bless you.
God, have you ever thought of
having this stuff cleaned?
I think about it constantly.
That comes with a surgical mask.
Don't be funny. What I have come
here to say is very serious.
You look great,
by the way.
And don't say flattering
things, either.
OK. I'll do my best. Anything
else I should try to avoid?
I'll tell you
as we go along.
How's Ellie?
Have you seen her?
I talked to her.
How is she?
Terrific.
Good.
How's Porter?
Fabulous.
One birch-bark canoe.
I'll take the canoe.
The canoe goes with
the house.
You hate the canoe.
I don't hate it.
You get seasick.
I like getting seasick.
Besides, the kids like--
The kids? Wait a minute.
We haven't talked about
the kids yet.
We're talking
about them now.
Could we talk about the children
later? That's a different issue.
The children are 65. They're old
enough to decide for themselves.
My daughter will decide she
wants to be with me.
Oh, so now you want
to split up the kids?
If that's what's fair,
that's fine.
OK, so fair? So what?
You want one kid and
one dog and half the canoe.
Good. A half a canoe
would be fine.
Porter, I don't think that that
would hold in any court.
Please, let's not
talk about courts.
Mona, you don't
have to tell me.
Yes, let me get this out.
Please, Griffin.
Don't fuck it up.
I am telling you,
there are some things
that are better left unsaid.
We don't need
to know everything.
Can you look me in the eye
and say there are some things
that are best
left unsaid?
Have you lost
your mind?!
After living
20 years of a lie
when the truth would
have served us better?
Knowing what I know,
at least I could have had
half a chance of a life with
somebody who wouldn't make me
feel like a failure.
Oh...
and I spent
all those... years
buying lingerie to--
Who'd you think
I was buying it for,
Griffin, you?
Some of it.
Well...
I felt cheap
in the red teddy.
OK, I've--
that's a joke.
Please.
Honey, please don't--
Mona, Mona, listen to me.
I know. I know.
You know?
Yes.
And it's OK.
Really?
Yes.
Oh, honey, you
know everything?
Yes.
Oh...
Oh, doesn't
this feel good?
Let's just
recapitulate.
The Lartique photographs,
the Stark chairs.
What about the, um,
season's tickets
to the Metropolitan?
Well, I'll take them.
I mean...
did you ever use them?
OK, that leaves
just one item:
a first edition of Fitzgerald's
Tender is the Night.
Did you ever read it?
I read it out loud
to you. You had pneumonia.
You cried
at the end.
Excuse me.
Women tend to respond
strongly to it.
It's very sentimental.
I cried, too.
I prefer Gatsby myself.
Did you ever read it
to your wife?
No. Actually, she doesn't
like the sound of my voice.
Did I say something funny?
No, you didn't.
You said something sad.
Well, I think
we've done very well here.
Don't you, Eleanor?
Yeah.
Porter?
Yes.
Very, very well.
Because, if you think
you've been treated unfairly
in this process--
It's been very fair.
Very fair.
After all, Porter,
if you hadn't--I mean...
none of this would have
happened if you hadn't--
I'm sorry. What?
Well, if he hadn't
done the...
all the things that...
if he...
you know, Ellie.
If he hadn't had--
had relations with--
Oh, come on!
He's right! He's right!
It's clear, look at it. I've
been a thoughtless sleazebag.
That's exactly right.
Look what I've done.
I've caused pain
to everybody in my life
my kids,
my innocent kids,
my friends,
everyone that I know.
My dogs! I've caused
pain to my dogs.
And clearly I must have been
willing to sacrifice everything
that meant anything
at all to me in my life.
Porter, let's not
go overboard, all right?
So you're not
the perfect person
you thought you were.
I have no idea
who I thought I was.
The only thing
that I know
is that I'm not
who I was when we met.
I'm not a kid. You know?
And I know now that
no empty philandering
is gonna make me
feel like one,
'cause the only thing
that I felt
when I tried it
was lonely. Just lonely.
I know I'd do anything to get
you back, but I've lost you.
I know that. I got to live
with that.
But you are who you were when we
met. You're just as beautiful,
you're just as smart,
and you're just as honest
as you were the day that
I fell in love with you.
And I am a fool.
And I know that.
So, is there
anything left?
There's a whole lot left.
Porter.
Well, what
did you expect, huh?
I mean, come on.
Is your marriage perfect?
Have you ever been a fool?
You got to keep trying, right?
You got to keep trying,
and keep hoping.
You got
to keep hoping, I mean...
Hello, Porter.
There's always
something left
if 2 people have ever
really loved each other.
And, uh...
I've never
loved anyone else.
Who knows? Maybe someday
she'll, uh...
let me back in the door.
Or, uh...
maybe after a while
she'll even let me upstairs.
But, uh, for now,
let's just hope she
lets me down off this roof.
* Oh, no one to talk with
* By myself
* No one to walk with
* I'm happy
on the shelf *
* Ain't misbehavin'
* Savin' my love
* Oh, bubba bubba
doodle da zydoo *
* I know for certain *
* The one I love
* I'm through flirtin' *
* It's you that
I'm thinking of *
* Ain't misbehavin'
* Savin' love *
* Boddle ah da da
doo doo dut *
* Yeah *
* Like Jack Horner
* In the corner
* Don't go nowhere *
* And I don't care
* All your kisses
* Are worth
a-waitin' for *
* Believe me *
* I don't stay out late *
* Don't care to go
* I'm home about 8.00
* Me and the radio
* I'll take a drummin',
drummin', y'all *